Goya's Ghosts is a drama, history film directed by Miloš Forman.
Painter Francisco Goya becomes involved with the Spanish Inquisition
after his muse, Inés, is arrested by the church for heresy.
Her family turns to him, hoping that his connection with fanatical
Inquisitor Lorenzo, whom he is painting, can secure her release.
Lorenzo Casamares, played by Javier Bardem.
Inés Bilbatúa / Alicia, played by Natalie Portman.
Francisco Goya, played by Stellan Skarsgård.
King Carlos IV, played by Randy Quaid.
Tomás Bilbatúa, played by José Luis Gómez.
Inquisitor General, played by Michael Lonsdale.
Goya's Ghosts is a 2006 biographical drama film, directed by Miloš Forman (his final directorial
feature before his death in 2018), and written by him and Jean-Claude Carrière.
The film stars Javier Bardem, Natalie Portman, and Stellan Skarsgård as
Francisco Goya, and was filmed on location in Spain during late 2005.
The film was written, produced, and performed in
English although it is a Spanish production.
Although the historical setting of the film is authentic, the story about Goya trying to defend a
model is fictional, as are the characters Brother Lorenzo and the Bilbatúa family.
The film explores themes of rape, religion and
supernatural, heresy, napoleon bonaparte, loss.
The tone is emotional.